[engine starts]
[Jerry] This is a 1970
Mercedes 280 SL in signal red.
It has a 170-horsepower,
straight 6 engine, 2.8 liters.
This was a car
for guys that want a sports car,
but don't really
wanna be inconvenienced.
It's an "I get what
the young people are doing
and I'm part of it,
but I will not be putting my mattress
on the floor."
[line rings]
Hello, Alec? It's Jerry.
[Alec] Hey. How are you, man?
What's going on?
[Jerry]
Do you wanna grab a coffee?
[Alec] Right now?
[Jerry] Yeah, I'll pick you up.
[Alec] I'll be downstairs
in what, 30 minutes?
[Jerry] Great.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld
and this is
Comedians in Cars getting Coffee.
Today my guest is Alec Baldwin.
Brilliant actor, movie star
and one of my all time
favorite funny people.
You look good.
Are you surprised?
[Jerry] Look at that Häagen-Dazs,
-look at that just sitting there.
-Yeah.
-That's a whole rack of Häagen-Dazs.
-That looks good.
-I gave up ice cream.
-I know.
You've never been fat
in your life, have you?
Have you?
Your life has been one unbroken boulevard
of green lights, hasn't it?
[Alec] You're from my hometown.
We're from the same town.
[Jerry] Right. Massapequa.
Who do you think has worked harder
to get where they are? You or me?
I think I've worked harder than you
and not gotten as far, quite frankly.
-That's how it works.
-What do you consider work?
Not walking into a room and everybody
just falls down and worships you.
Really?
[chuckles] "Really?
That?"
-[Alec] Do you eat there?
-[Jerry] Not anymore.
I have.
I'm gonna steal that.
Burt Lancaster.
I don't remember whose story it is.
They came up to his house,
and he came to the door,
and his first line was, "Muffin, Bob?"
My favorite Burt Lancaster story was
when they went to Burt Lancaster's trailer
on the movie Tough Guys with Kirk Douglas.
And they had a stack of glossies
of the two of them to sign.
And the kid knocks on the door,
and Burt Lancaster says, "Come in."
And they come in with a pen,
and Burt Lancaster's gonna sign them
and he goes... [imitating Lancaster]
"Never mind. I got my own pen."
And he takes out a big, thick Sharpie
and signs "Burt Lancaster" on the picture.
He signs a stack of them, and he leaves.
-They go to Kirk Douglas' trailer.
-[knocks]
They knock on the door.
He says, "Come in."
They open the door, he comes in
with a stack, they hand him the pen.
And he writes it and his signature's
so puny next to it, he goes,
[imitating Douglas]
"Can't you give me the pen that he had?"
They go back to Burt Lancaster's trailer
and they knock on the door,
and Burt Lancaster comes with the pen
in his hand and goes,
-"I suppose you're looking for this."
-[chuckles]
The two of them just [bleep]
with each other on every level.
[imitating Lancaster]
"I suppose you're looking for this."
[Jerry] What was the TV commercial
that you spent months trying to find?
I tried to find the voice of a man
who was...
He was a booth announcer.
Back in the old days when I was a kid.
They had booth announcers.
That way, if all that equipment,
if something got gummed up
and they had a ma who'd be like...
[clears throat]
"We are expecting technical difficulties.
We'll be back in a moment."
The booth announcer I loved
was a guy named Robert Molly.
In the end of Million Dollar Movie,
Robert Molly would come on
to tell you what tomorrow's
million dollar movie would be.
And he'd say... [imitating Molly]
"Barbara Stanwyck gives
Kirk Douglas a piece of her mind tomorrow
on Million Dollar Movie."
And that was the voice of my childhood.
And you wanted us to hear that again?
I found it. Took me six months,
and I found it.
We'll be back in a moment with
The Joe Franklin Show.
[Jerry laughs]
Have you seen the poster
for the new Three Stooges?
The Three Stooges was something
that even I could only take
in little spurts.
Were you a Three Stooges fan?
-I wasn't.
-I wasn't, either.
Moe made me uncomfortable.
Whenever someone would strike someone
with a metallic object.
Like you hit someone
with a ball-pein hammer...
-Yeah.
-...you lost-- I turn the channel.
Do you run the garage?
Do you guys have a coffee shop here?
-[Jerry chuckles]
-No?
-Coffee.
-I think I'll have a cappuccino.
[waitress] Okay.
I'd like a tuna salad sandwich
on some rye toast.
I have a seven-grain, is that okay?
That's the only kind of bread you have?
-Seven grain.
-You only have seven-grain?
[indistinct]
We're not gonna get into a Jack Nicholson,
Five Easy Pieces kind of thing here,
-are we?
-[Jerry chuckles]
Let's start all over again.
What do you have?
-Seven grain--
-That sounds perfect.
[waitress] Do you want it toasted?
[imitates Jack Nicholson]
"I want chicken salad."
[waitress] What do you want?
We'll give you what we have.
"What do you want? We'll give you
what we have." That's brilliant.
I'm gonna be 54-years-old
in about three weeks.
And I literally now
wake up every day and say to myself,
"What do I wanna do
with the time I have left?"
-Yeah.
-That list of "I have to do this
"and I have to do this in my life"
is getting shorter.
-Right.
-But the stuff that's on that list,
-I really do have to do those things.
-Right.
We were sitting on my back patio one time
and you said,
"If I had a joint like this, I would set
up a phone right here and just go..."
"No. No."
When was the first time you got up
in front of an audience and performed?
-I was 21-years-old.
-What place?
Catch a Rising Star, 1st Avenue
and 78th. You must've gone there a lot.
-I know Catch.
-Right.
But there was nothing more amazing to me.
There was nothing.
I was transfixed
by open mic comedy night
-at Good Times.
-Really?
You never wanted to be a straight actor?
Just legit acting?
Were you ever tempted during your career?
Did you ever sit there and go,
"I wanna try..."
-Well, I did act.
-That was a good reading, by the way.
-What?
-Good reading. "Well, I did act."
I mean, wow.
-I have five different awards.
-Do you?
They're not from organizations
you'll recognize, but I have them.
The American Association of Retailers.
I've said this to you before,
that your great gift
is the rapier-like comic skill...
-What was that word?
-Rapier-like.
R-a-p-i-e-r, hyphen, l-i--
-Oh, rapier.
-Rapier. I say "rapier."
-No? "Rapier?"
-That's really pretentious or wrong.
Rapier could get you in trouble.
It could be misconstrued.
-Rapier-like skills.
-Rapier is two rapists talking.
-Yeah, exactly.
-"You think you're rapier than me?"
-Right, exactly. "You don't know rapier."
-No...
"My cellmate at Rahway,
he was the rapiest guy."
[waitress] A tuna fish, not on rye.
[Alec]
"A tuna fish, not on rye." You're funny.
You know what I need from you,
if you don't mind?
-May I have a fork and some napkins?
-Absolutely.
-Do you have any pickles?
-[waitress] We have pickles.
Could we get a bowl of pickles?
-That was--
-I wanna get a bowl of pickles.
And I wanna have a fork.
I'd like some kind of dinnerware here,
flatware.
Is that gonna be a problem?
Do you want me to start crying?
So, you wanna talk about
this acting thing?
But I wanna talk about why...
First of all, you're looking at me,
you know me well enough,
you can look in my eyes,
you can see it's not there.
You're not looking at me and going,
"You know, you have something
that hasn't been tapped."
That's not true.
You're looking at me thinking,
"Whatever you have has been used."
-No, that's not true.
-Okay, fine.
I look at you and I say,
"He's a lazy bastard.
"He has everything in the world
he could possibly want.
"And he's just a lazy, shiftless,
no-good bastard."
-That's not true.
-Yeah.
What are you asking me about?
Doing serious stuff?
Do I have the urge to do
something straight, dramatic?
I'm considered one
of the most articulate people
in the Screen Actors Guild today.
You seem to be having trouble
understanding what I'm saying.
-Why do you think that is?
-You're looking at me,
"This is a kid from Massapequa."
A kid from Bar Harbor.
-You remember the Slip'N Slide?
-Yes.
You know, the Slip'n Slide, you run,
and then you stop running
and continue moving forward.
When I was a kid, that blew my mind.
In my neighborhood,
we were staring over our fences,
staring at other people's Slip'n Slides.
"That [bleep] Jerry got a [bleep]
Slip'n Slide! That hard-on.
Look at that Slip'n Slide.
Can you imagine?
"Jeez."
"Must be nice."
"Is anybody out here using it?
Anybody playing it?
He's in the house. What's he doing?
Look through the window.
He's talking into a hairbrush
in his bathroom."
[Jerry laughing]
I remember when I was a kid,
my brothers would play wiffle ball
in the driveway, and I worked.
Now, I would leave my house at ten o'clock
in the morning in the summertime.
Is the picture you're painting for me here
that it was tough economically?
No, it was gonna lead me up
to what trash my brothers were.
'Cause they would be playing wiffle ball
in the driveway at ten a.m.,
and when I came back
at four o'clock in the afternoon,
they were still playing
the same game of wiffle ball.
They played wiffle ball
for six hours in the [bleep] driveway.
So, you were the more responsible one.
I was Abraham Lincoln to them.
Yeah. And they were all John Wilkes Booth.
What's it like being a dad for you?
Being a dad is, is, you know,
it's a surfboard on a rainbow.
You're getting all you can handle of life.
What I like about having kids
is when they're on the toilet
and you knock on the door,
they just go, "Come in."
Nobody else does that.
Nobody just invites you in
while they're on the toilet...
-defecating.
-Yeah.
The demographic for the Academy is
very, very interesting.
I went there, and I hosted the Oscars,
and you'd have people walk up to you,
it is very touching.
I was moved, and a guy
would walk up to you that was...
80-years-old.
This guy went to shake my hand,
he goes,
[imitating man] "I'm Bob Tucker,
I was a stunt coordinator on
She Wore a Yellow Ribbon.
And I just wanna say
thank you very much for doing this.
It means the world to us that
you're taking the time out of your--"
Cut to the next woman...
[imitating woman] "I'm Muriel Wittingham.
I was the art director on Vertigo."
And you go, " Oh, my God".
You're gonna get to change the whole thing
from the bottom up. What would you do?
What would the better Oscar show be?
It would be two-hours long.
And you'd have a lot
of reverence for film,
and you'd have it be much more serious.
-You think that would work?
-No. That's the problem.
-Would you ever host the Oscars?
-No.
-You would never.
-You wouldn't get near it?
-No.
"Can I get more iced tea?"
"Hello, no."
"Thank you, Roger."
If you're producing and I can talk to you
during the broadcast,
and you're off-camera there...
-Like Fred de Cordova.
-Sure.
-I'll be your Rip Torn.
-Yeah.
Rip Torn did a part in Bee Movie with me.
I love that guy.
He's doing the show with me and I go,
"Where do you live?"
He goes... [imitates Rip]
"I live up there in Salisbury."
I said, "What's it like where you live?"
He literally said to me,
[imitates Rip] "Some of the people
up there are a little strange.
One time I was in a bar up there
and these two guys are at the bar,
and they gave me the eye, see?
And I knew something was gonna go down."
I'm sitting there going,
"What? What happened?"
He goes, "I started to go out the door
and go to the car,
and the one guy makes a move on me,
so I crack him in the jaw.
The other guy smashes me
with a bottle in the face.
I kick the other guy in the balls.
I stick a fork in the other..."
He's describing this
Peckinpah-esque melee.
My mouth is on the floor.
I go, "When did this happen?"
He went...
[imitates Rip] "Last summer."
You know, he's like 74. He is...
-That's great.
-Yeah, he's crazy. He's crazy.
This, by the way, is your curse.
And I say this about you all the time.
You're a gifted, gifted actor,
who is cursed with the mind of a writer.
I've gotten more, uh, into that
as a result of being around
the people I've been around.
I don't think I'm that funny,
but I'm totally comfortable when I say,
"I learned a lot
from being around them for six years.
They taught me a lot."
What you know cannot be taught, my friend.
-Well, in some ways, I appreciate that.
-Just take the compliment.
You realize we have to leave Rebecca
a $1,000 tip? Do you know that?
This is the situation we painted.
-I moved downtown. It's very strange.
-[Jerry] Tell me how it's going.
Oh, it's so strange.
In your apartment,
at three o'clock in the morning, you hear,
[imitates woman] "[bleep] you, Steven!
Steven! Get back here!"
Like a full five minutes go by
and then it's,
[imitates woman]
"[bleep] you, Steven!"
I'm like,
"She's still at [bleep] you, Steven."
-Like it's a pot that's just boiling.
-That's the energy of youth.
Only youth can give you that.
Only young people
can keep those flames burning,
those pots boiling all that time.
[Alec imitating woman]
"[bleep] you, Steven!
Steven, get back here!"